CURRICULUM VITAE



DIEGO RUIZ

Address:

Ølgod Kirkenvaenget 9B

Zip Code:

6870 Varde Kommune

Other personal info



+45 28 59 29 68



differ454@hotmail.com



github.com/DiegoRuiz454



linkedin.com/in/diegoruiz454/

SKILLS

HTML/CSS

JavaScript

Git

MySQL

NodeJS

React JS

ARDUINO

LADDER(PLC SOFTWARE)

LANGUAGES

Spanish English

Danish (process Learning)

PROFILE

Fullstack software developer and electronics technologist with more than 4 years of experience generating code for companies in the production and educational sector. I worked 6 months for The Little Music School as a NodeJS full stack developer, from February to July 2021, where i helped developing most of the Backend REST API for the booking site called bulowsvej10.dk.

I am specialist in problem solving, teamwork and implementation of ideas for improvements, respect for Other people, punctuality and humility are very important values that I take into account.

WORK EXPERIENCE

02/2021 - 06/2021 Leonardo Udvikling Aps Copenhagen Denmark

Tasks:

- Creating Signup, Login and Session, as well as Forgotten password flow with automatic e-mail and SMS integration.
- Create mobile app Open door integration, that based on users GPS location and login.
- Credentials would open the schools door.
- Implement cancel subscription and delete user REST end points.
- Implement logging and error handling.
- Conversion of a code created with PHP technology to NodeJS.

Technologies used:

- Progressive Web Apps (PWA).
- Material UI components for frontend development.
- Sequelize Object Relational Mapping (ORM) framework for MariaDB.
- OpenAPI specification for REST API's using the Swagger UI tools.
- Plesk for server administration of: Apache, Nginx, MariaDB, Passenger Node application server.
- Professional development process with: development, testing, staging and production setup.
- Kanboard tool for agile project management based on Scrum.
- Visual Studio Code.

06/2016- 07/2019 ABinBev Company (Beer factory Colombia)

(brands: Budweiser, Corona, Stella Artois, Beck's)

Tasks:

- Implementation of software created with visual basic to standardize production methods within the company.
- Electronic maintenance, Software programmer for production systems with plc and microprocessors, sensors, physiochemical laboratory analyst.

01/2015 - 02/2016 School Maria Montessori - Tulua / Colombia

Tasks:

-Teacher of electronics, mathematics and physics.

EDUCATION

06/2020 – 02/2021 - HackYourFuture – Copenhagen / Denmark Full Stack Web Development: HTML, CSS, Javascript, MySQL, Git, Node js, Postman, express, React js.

06/2010 – 12/2014 University of Valle – Tulua / Colombia Electronic Technologist :

Design, development, implementation and adaptation of technological solutions for the automation of processes in the manufacturing industry and telecommunications.